<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Longitudinal Ship Stability</string>
    <string name="lcb_string">LCB(Longitudinal Centre of Buoyancy): It is regarded as the geometric center of the volume of the zone remaining under water and is the point through which all the buoyancy can be said to act vertically upwards.</string>
    <string name="lcg_string">LCG(Longitudinal Centre of Gravity): This is the point through which all of the weight of the vessel can be said to act vertically downwards.</string>
    <string name="lcf_string">LCF(Longitudinal Center of Floatation): Vessels are not generally symmetrical fore and aft, so they do not necessarily rotate about amidships when trimming. In fact, they rotate about a point called the LCF that is the centre of the shape of the waterline at which the vessel is floating.</string>
    <string name="longitudinal_intro_string">When we are loading or unloading a ship, or when we transfer a load from one point to another, the drafts of the ship will change. Here we will learn how to calculate the varying drafts of the vessels because of these cargo operations by examining the longitudinal stability of the vessels.</string>
    <string name="breadth_string">It is called the largest width of a ship.</string>
    <string name="depth_string">The mastory section (the cross section of the keel between the perpendiculars) and the vertical distance measured between the keel and the main deck on the shipboard.</string>
    <string name="draught_string">Mean draught (in mastory section) is the distance between the keel and the water line.Fore and aft draughts are the distance between the keel and the water line passing through the fore and aft draught marks.</string>
    <string name="buoyancy_string">Center of buoyancy  is the geometric center of a zone under water. This point is indicated by the letter B. With the effect of the water lifting force, the ship is pushed vertically upwards from this center. </string>
    <string name="gravity_string">The center of gravity is the point where the vertical forces that make up the weight of the gathers are gathered. This point is symbolized by the letter G. We can also define the center of gravity as "the center of the ship mass". In the center of gravity, there is a force that draws a ship floating vertically down the water. This force equals the weight of the ship. The weights of the ship is called displacement, symbolized by  Δ.</string>
    <string name="stability_intro_string">According to the Archimedes Law, an object in the water will want to sink into the water with a force of weight and will be pushed upwards with a force equal to the weight of the water displaced. If these two forces are equal to each other, the object will not sink into water and float in balance. The stability of a ship is defined by the determination of two points. These are the centers of gravity and buoyancy.</string>
    <string name="kgkb_string">As you can see figure,  the forces acting perpendicular to the ship from these centers are on the opposite side and equal to each other. Also  the center of gravity is located above the center of float ability on a normal ship. KG > KB.</string>
</resources>
